okay here we go
okay don't forget you're in a group and
try not to move
relax your forehead relax your smile
pull in your stomach slightly shoulders
back fingers relaxed
ice soft if you feel sleepy maybe open
them a little bit
and then we'll come to our breath ten
long exhales and let the Indians take
care of themselves
please bring you and one of your
teachers to the room to sit with you the
main thing is they're just very happy
that you're meditating and that you're
asking
and bow down to your teacher by thinking
about some beautiful quality you enjoy
about them
and make offering something good you've
done or something good you've seen
didn't open your heart and tell them
about any mistake you've made especially
in the last few days you hurt someone
and something nice you've done something
nice you've seen somebody do don't be
lazy about this one
find something sweet that you've done
being here at the mountain is a big
thing to take all the trouble to come
here
ask the teacher to teach you keep
teaching
you asked them to stay with you
now I'd like you to check in with your
mind
it's a morning mind at a very quiet
place time and probably our mind is
pretty smooth glossy the water of the
mind is pleasant quiet so we just
observe it for about 10 or 20 breaths
observe what the quiet morning mind
looks like
we've been talking about different
triggers for Glacius negative emotions
for example he brought someone in the
room that we don't like but we thought
about our addictions we also talked
about the trigger of old
old mental sections all negative
emotions that tend to repeat each other
we talked about bad friends
and good friends as triggering our
negative emotions we talked about being
busy thinking about many things we have
to do which can trigger negativity in
our mind and today what I'd like to do
is go back in your knife and try to
think of the first person you can
remember that you had trouble with who
who gave you some trouble
like for me I grew up with four brothers
and we loved each other very much but we
also had many fights and trouble with
each other
so I'd like you to go back in your life
and think about what was the first
person in your life when you were very
young that you used to get angry and
powder and used to have trouble with
them so we'll spend about four or five
minutes go back in your life as early as
you can and find one of the first people
you used to have trouble
here we go
and I'd like you to think about early
addictions maybe it was there some kind
of food or other addiction but what was
your first addiction that you can think
of when you were just a job
now please come to you instead of mine
look at your state of mind how's the
water become more agitated or jumpy
compared to when we started when we
started I think most of us had a very
clear smooth glassy state of mind what
the water in the mind then we thought
about someone who gave us trouble very
early then we thought about little
addictions we had as a child and even
just thinking about those things has
stirred up old memories stirred up old
feelings so please take a look at those
feelings and compare it to the early
morning mine how is the water become
more stirred up
and then finally if I met a person when
I was so young that bothered me and if
things are coming from me like a pen
then what kind of thing that I do to
create this person when did I have time
to plant those seeds and what did I
maybe do in my past life to meet someone
when I'm so young who would stir up my
mind give me a pleasure so try to
imagine maybe how we created these
people in our early early life or how
did we have an addiction already when
we're so young what did I do in my past
life so try to guess what you might have
done in your personal to have this
addiction so young or to meet someone so
young today they gave me trouble okay
here we go
think about the causes in the past life
we might have planted
then please get back your bath three non
exhales to share the good karma of your
meditation it's really long exhales
don't open your eyes and don't move yet
and slowly open your eyes take a stretch
during something
I think if you had brothers and sisters
then that's automatically the glacier
producer in your early life but anybody
like to share about the first one they
remember
[Music]
ah Thank You Joshua I can remember my
first phone have a trouble is my younger
brother
we always fight at home and then when
you leave us go to the last go to the
you know past life and when I fight with
my brother
I always think he just give me Chapel
don't let me do whatever I want so then
go to the past life I feel that maybe I
also be a irritating people for someone
like I always control they don't don't
want them to do that today so I think
for right now I also have this kind of
things like like now I with my father
also I love him a lot but so funny is
when I go to pay a visit with him
sometimes we fight my father say
something I will automatic field unhappy
so um thank you this meditation helped
me to find something yeah I might need
to do something with this this problem
thank you so much
I had my grandfather come to me when I
was a little girl maybe for my my
grandfather who was polish it with
ja-cheol I went to him and I told him
something that had happened that was
true and he looked at me and he said no
that didn't happen and he just went
right over my head and he insisted on a
different scenario from what this little
four-year-old girl knew was true and I
was so shocked I was like my grandfather
it's just not understanding what is true
so I don't know past life I must have
been some kind of despereaux or
something you know some oligarch or
bureaucrat that was just making people
do things that had nothing to do with
reality and forced it on them okay
Sheila I inclusionary years remember is
like a bit over a year old I went out
with my grandma and I just need another
child on the road and Iranians
yeah if you're scared and they got back
home hide because their parents had to
coming to search for me and I had a
distant memory so it's a kind of
irritating and a fear inside and the
addition is many about the food
especially like a special kind of food
crisis him to your things and to the
earlier previous lives it's back to
almost a 2000 years ago I was a king's I
either life I died like fifty years old
with like a seven to eight wife no kids
so I have a kind of irritating mind to
see I have so many wives I don't have
any kid you are so unable to give me the
kids say the kind of negative a judgment
I have that a lot today so I I found the
crew is like since the the other that
has not a bother me so obviously but I
continuously to give negative judgment
and to make negative actions little so
that's my issues
thank you thank you Anna for teaching
can stay integers for me it was hard to
remember any irritating person before
age of seven or eight so it seems like I
was
by that time I needed to go up a little
bit in the meditation like to go to nine
or ten years addiction I didn't find
unless addition to books I dunno it was
I was collecting books Tina I was young
and the editing person unfortunately was
my father who used to be very angry all
the time until now I can say and I think
this is my seeds for a misunderstanding
from past life because I was extremely
angry for anything so in this short
meditation helped me a little bit to
release this pension to him because he
is my sage and I have been going to the
lower middle school long time before
avoiding him but no is no way to avoid
it anymore so thank you for this and I
just felt like sharing it with you okay
thank you
okay we're gonna go to the text okay and
it's gonna give us some help about this
if you look at your meditation sheets
there's a number 11 it's a holding a
sword find it what page page five okay
and there's a sword we're gonna go
through this six triggers for negative
emotions and today we did seeds today we
looked at seeds so maybe from your past
life
you already had some anger or you were
angry to other people or in your past
life you had already some addiction I
don't know for me it was sweets and so
that's what we explored today
second one is proximity it means when
the person who irritates you is close by
or the hotel that you like is close by
then it tends to cause the negative
emotions nearby third one is over
stimulation and that's where we're too
busy and thinking about too many things
and it tends to support our negative
emotions fourth one is friends what's
that mean yeah bad friends people who
are nearby us and cause us trouble when
we're around them five and six we didn't
really do yet so I'm gonna save that for
tomorrow okay